AMIYA RANJAN **DAS**

Bangalore, Karnataka

2 +91 8235251090

in amiya-ranjan-das

I am a Front-end Developer with 4+ years of experience in the R&D Software Industry, with an M. Tech focused on Software Engineering from BITS, Pilani. Passionate about crafting engaging and user-friendly digital experiences with a keen eye for design and a strong grasp of the latest web technologies.

EXPERIENCE

OCT 2021 - PRESENT (2.5 years)

DEVELOPER, SAP LABS

Being a part of SAP UX S4 HANA team, my responsibilities were.

- Developing a new Home Page for S4 HANA, which is used as the central point of launchpad for any application of S4 HANA suite.
- Continues enhancements on the home page with a lot of new features like drag & drop of items, full screen view, animations and providing personalization of the tool to each user.
- Maintaining and fixed bugs and handling customer tickets.
- Being involved in multiple development tasks such as user research, planning, design & release.

JAN 2020 - SEP 2021 (1.5 years)

ASSOCIATE DEVELOPER, SAP LABS

Being a part of SAP UX UI5 team, my responsibilities were.

- Developing new features and controls for SAP's front-end framework SAP UI5, which is used by all the fiori applications across different teams.
- Developing different fiori elements and reusable suite controls for the core framework SAP UI5.
- Creating graphical controls to visualize complex network structures using D3 library.
- Unit testing using karma.

AUG 2017 – DEC 2019 (2.5 years)

SCHOLAR@SAP, SAP LABS

Scholar@SAP is a globally recognized WILP in partnership with BITS Pilani. Where I had the opportunity to rotate across different SAP business areas and explore different technologies.

- Contributed to migration of SAP Business Object dashboard from adobe flash to latest technologies. Developed a new analytics dashboard using SAP UI5 framework.
- Contributed in SAP API Management to develop the user interface.
- Consume REST APIs to and performing CRUD operations.
- CI/CD of the application on SAP Cloud Platform.

EDUCATION

2017 - 2021

M. TECH (SOFTWARE ENGINEERING), BITS PILANI

CGPA - 7.1

2014 - 2017

BCA, ST. XAVIER'S COLLEGE RANCHI

Percentage - 79%

2012 - 2014

12TH, SURENDRANATH CENTENARY SCHOOL RANCHI

Percentage – 78%

SKILLS

- Web Technologies HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Typescript
- Frameworks/Libraries React, jQuery, D3.js, SAP UI5, SAP Fiori apps
- Tools & techs Git/Github, SAP Cloud Platform, npm
- REST APIs, Odata, Agile Development, Cross Browser Testing & Debugging, Responsive UI.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Got Praise Award for 2023 Q2.
- Got Value Award for 2020 Q2.
- Got Praise Award for 2019 Q3.
- Finalist in hackathon InnoVision 2k18, worked on the project of IoT Connected Goods.